safenet-inc.com 2005-12-19

# Privacy Information

| 

    Solutions  

| | 

  Products  

| | 

  Support  

| | 

  About SafeNet  

| | 

  News and Media  

| | 

  Partners  

| | 

  Library  

| | 

  Careers  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
| 

### Copyright

Unless otherwise noted, all information on SafeNet Web Sites is copyright©2004 by SafeNet, Inc.

### SafeNet and the E.U. - U.S. Safe Harbor for Privacy

The European Commission and the U.S. Department of Commerce have developed a "safe harbor" framework of data protection principles ("Safe Harbor"). This Safe Harbor is designed to provide U.S. organizations with a means to satisfy the European Union's legal requirement that adequate data protections be afforded to personally-identifiable information transferred from the European Union to the United States. SafeNet's Privacy Policy is consistent with the Safe Harbor principles, and SafeNet has certified that its transfers of data from the European Union to the United States adhere to the Safe Harbor principles. 

**Notice**  
In general, you may browse through our site without providing us any information about yourself. However, we may request Personal Information on occasion in order to provide you with specific services or information that you have requested. "Personal Information" is information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person that identifies that person. At the time SafeNet collects Personal Information from you, it will inform you of the purposes for which it collects and uses such information and how to contact SafeNet with any inquiries or complaints. SafeNet will not disclose Personal Information to third parties, other than its wholly owned subsidiaries, which are subject to this same Privacy Policy. 

**Choice**  
SafeNet will offer you the opportunity to choose whether your Personal Information is to be (a) disclosed to a third party or (b) used for a purpose that is incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. Generally, SafeNet does not disclose your Personal Information to third parties. 

**Security**  
SafeNet will take reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. 

**Data Integrity**  
SafeNet will not process your Personal Information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by you. To the extent necessary for those purposes, SafeNet will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is relevant for its intended use, accurate, complete and current. 

**Access**  
SafeNet will provide you with reasonable access to your Personal Information that it holds and will undertake reasonable steps to permit you to correct, amend or delete that information demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. 

Transfer to Third Parties  
When SafeNet transfers information to a third party that is acting as an agent, before doing so it will ascertain that the third party either safeguards Personal Information consistent with this Privacy Policy, is subject to the EU Directive 95/46/EC (the EU Data Protection Directive, Safe Harbor certification in the U.S by the third party, or by being subject to another European Commission adequacy finding). Alternatively, SafeNet may enter into a written agreement with such third party requiring that the third party provide at least the same level of privacy protection as required by the relevant principles of this Policy. Where SafeNet has knowledge that an agent is using or disclosing personal information contrary to this Policy, SafeNet will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure. 

**Enforcement**  
SafeNet will conduct compliance audits of its relevant privacy practices to verify adherence to this policy. Any employee that SafeNet determines is in violation of this policy will be subject to disciplinary action. 

**Dispute Resolution**  
Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of Personal Information should be directed to the Legal Department at legal@safenet-inc.com. SafeNet will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints regarding use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved between you and SafeNet, SafeNet has agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European data protection authorities to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Principles. 

**What data we collect and how we use it**  
SafeNet generally collects information for the following purposes: 

  * **To engage in transactions and communications.** Name, address, email, purchase details, and credit card/payment information may be collected and stored as a necessary part of an online transaction and its attendant history. SafeNet may need to share some of this information (address, etc.) with fulfillment houses, credit card clearing houses, and other similarly situated third parties as a requirement to complete a transaction.
  * **To provide future service and support.** Contact and other information related to products and services may be collected to assist future needs and customer support for SafeNet. This information is also used to provide product and service updates, and similar notices.
  * **To respond to user inquiries and requests for information.**
  * **To provide useful marketing information.** We may use information from you to provide timely and relevant notices of corporate events, product releases and updates, and service developments.
  * **To provide additional information on corporate events or related products.** We occasionally use your information to provide you with details on events and products that may meet your needs.

**Cookies**  
When you visit SafeNet's website, you can browse the site anonymously. To recognize you, to improve our service to you on subsequent visits, and for web tracking purposes, we use cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data that a Web server transfers to your browser and can only be read by that server. We do not use cookies to obtain personal identification information or data from your computer's hard drive. Cookies cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses. Most browsers are initially configured to accept cookies. You can set your browser to let you know you when you receive a cookie or even prevent your browser from receiving all cookies. However, if your browser cannot receive cookies, you may limit the functionality we can provide when you visit our site. 

**Employment and Employee Data**  
In addition to the foregoing, the following applies to Employment/Employee Data collected by SafeNet or its subsidiaries. 

Employment/Employee Data includes any information about an identified or identifiable person that is obtained in the context of a person's working relationship, including the application and interview process prior to hiring with a SafeNet entity or third party vendor. Persons protected include job applicants, employees (including temporary, permanent and part-time), interns, contingent workers, retirees, and former employees, as well as any dependents or others whose personal data has been given to a SafeNet entity by such persons. Employment/Employee Data may be collected, stored, analyzed, shared and used for legitimate human resources, business, and safety/security purposes in accordance with this Policy and applicable law(s). The primary purposes for collection, storage and/or use of data include: 

  * **Human Resources Management:** involves the collection, storage, analysis and sharing of data in order to attract, retain and motivate a highly qualified workforce. This includes, but is not limited to, recruiting, compensation planning, succession planning, reorganization needs, performance assessment, training, employee benefit administration, compliance with applicable legal requirements, and communication with employees and/or their representatives.
  * **Business Processes and Management:** involves processes used to run SafeNet's operations to include, but is not limited to, scheduling work assignments, managing company assets, reporting and/releasing public data (e.g., Annual Reports, etc.); and populating employee directories.
  * **Safety and Security Management:** involves activities that ensure the safety and protection of employees, assets, resources, and communities.

SafeNet will ensure adequate protection for Employment/Employee Data processed or transferred between SafeNet entities. SafeNet entities may transfer Employment/Employee Data to selected external third parties that have been engaged to perform certain employment-related services. These third parties may only process the data in accordance with the SafeNet entity's instructions (data processors) or make decisions (e.g., to assess eligibility for supplemental life insurance, short-term disability benefit, etc.) regarding the data as part of the delivery of their services (data controllers). In either instance, SafeNet entities will select reliable suppliers who undertake, by contract or other legally binding and permissible means, to put in place appropriate technical and organizational security measures to ensure an adequate level of protection commensurate with their status as data processors or data controllers. SafeNet entities will require external third party suppliers to comply with this Policy or to guarantee the same levels of protection as SafeNet when handling this data. Such selected third parties will have access to this data solely for the purposes of performing the services specified in the applicable service contract. If a SafeNet entity concludes that a supplier is not complying with these obligations, it will promptly take appropriate actions to remedy such non-compliance or implement necessary sanctions. Occasionally, SafeNet entities may also be required to disclose certain Employment and/or Employee Data to other third parties as a matter of law (e.g., to tax and social security authorities, garnishments, etc.); to protect SafeNet's legal rights (e.g., to defend a litigation suit); or in an emergency where the health or security of an employee is endangered. 

### Safe Harbor Statement 

**Risk Factors**  
The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995 provides a "safe harbor" for forward-looking statements. Certain information included in our Annual Report on Form 10-K and other materials filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission ("SEC") (as well as information included in oral statements or other written statements made or to be made by the Company) contain statements relating to the following: acquisition strategy, dependence upon existing and new product offerings, competition, patents, intellectual property and licensing, future growth, rapid technological and market change, manufacturing and sourcing risks, Internet infrastructure and regulation, international operations, volatility of stock price, financial risk management and potential volatility in operating results, among others. These conditions involve important factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from those expressed in any forward-looking statements made by or on behalf of the Company. Any forward-looking statements are made pursuant to the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995 and, as such, speak only as of the date made. Statements made in this document that are not purely historical are forward-looking statements, including any statements as to beliefs, plans, expectations, or intentions regarding the future. The Company assumes no obligation to update information concerning its expectations.

### Terms of Use

**Disclaimer of Liability**  
SafeNet, Inc. is providing this site and its contents on an "as is" basis and makes no representations or warranties of any kind with respect to this site or its content.

Likewise, SafeNet, Inc. disclaims any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of any information, procedure, method, apparatus, product, or process posted on the site. Neither SafeNet, Inc., its employees, nor associates assumes any responsibility for loss or damages resulting from the use of information contained on this site. 

**Proprietary Rights and Trademarks**  
The text and images of people, products, or places displayed on this site are the property of either SafeNet, Inc., or a third party. The use of these images and/or text by you, or anyone authorized by you, is prohibited unless you obtain the express, written permission of SafeNet, Inc. Any unauthorized use of these images and/or text may violate copyright laws, trademark and service mark laws, the laws of privacy and publicity, and communications regulations and statutes.

The trademarks, logos, and service marks ("collectively the Trademarks") displayed on the site, including but not limited to SafeNet, are registered trademarks or trademarks of SafeNet, Inc. and others. No trademark displayed on the site may be used without the written permission of the party that owns that trademark. SafeNet, Inc., will aggressively enforce its intellectual property rights to the fullest extent of the law, including the seeking of criminal prosecution where authorized.

|  |   
---  
---  
  
**Contact Us**
